

# ROMAIN GIOUX

Web Developer



www.romaingioux.dev



romaingiouxdev@gmail.com



+33 698 117 167



59 drusbergstrasse 8053 Zürich, Switzerland



Work & Residency: B Permit

### LAST POSITION

Project Management Officer Disability Support Worker

Tea Cup Cottage - Capalaba, Australia MAY 2018 - JUNE 2020

Within the Blue Tongue Adventure program, the project was to open a cafe and a shared garden to provide professional training for young adults with a disability.

- Researched a new space.
- Supervised works to adapt the premise.
- Implemented safety regulations and risk policies.
- Logistic coordination to run activities and training for clients.

## LANGUAGES

French English Spanish

German



### PROFFSSIONAL PROFILE

Aiming for a career reconversion after 15 years as operational manager, I spent my last 2 years learning how the web is built and how I can contribute to make it a pleasant space.

I'm specialized in front end web development with a strong grasp of modern JavaScript ES6+. I love to create animated web environment and build interactive user interface powered by modern technologies. Furthermore technical SEO, clean code and testing are also essential for me to produce a complete achievement.

Back end awareness help me to build full stack application including user authentification, database flow and server communication.

As Self-taught, my challenge is to turn this enthusiasm and commitment into a professional activity, gain experiences by creating complex projects and join an ambitious team.

# **EDUCATION / TRAINING**

Web Development Training: since OCTOBER 2019 OpenClassrooms, online courses, tutorials, official documentation...

**En General English Certificat:** FEBRUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018 Intensive English courses B2+: Australian Pacific College, Brisbane

🚠 Humanitarian Logistic Bachelor : SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2014 Supply chain coordination training: Bioforce Institute - France

₩ High School Certificate : JULY 2004

Civil Engineering Science: Gilbert Romme High School, France

## COMPUTING SKILLS



#### **FRONT END:**

JavaScript / React / SEO HTML / CSS / SASS / SVG Responsive / Bootstrap GSAP / Cypress / Jest



#### **BACK END:**

Node.js / Mongo DB / SQL Firebase / Netlify / Heroku



#### CROSSOVER:

VS Code / Git Hub / NPM CompasMongoDB / Dev Tools MySQLworkbench / FTP WordPress / Shopify Mac OS / Windows Figma / Photoshop AutoCAD / Sketchup

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Technical Draftsman

OCTOBER 2017 - JANUARY 2018

Rector Lesage Group - Ravel, France

In charge of technical review in the engineering office of a factory for concrete element prefabrication.

- Established work plans on AutoCad software to create modular concrete floorings and beams.
- Evaluated and diagnosed customers requests, provided estimates, elements sizing and work plans.

Quality control Technician

OCTOBER 2016 - AUGUST 2017

CEMB - VICAT Cement Group - Fillinges, France

In charge of concrete quality control for a building materials laboratory after an internal training.

- Normalized and certified tests for all kind of concretes produced in 10 concrete production units.
- Analysed the test results, monitored, reported and followed up with customers.

Technical Salesman

MAY 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

L'Entrepôt du Bricolage - Annemasse, France

In charge of customer technical advisory and sales on building materials.

Order management and storage process.

Humanitarian Logistic Manager

SEPTEMBER 2014 - MARCH 2016

Doctors Without Borders - Geneva, Switzerland

Construction Project Manager: Boga, Democratic Republic of Congo (3 months)

Monitored and implemented rehabilitations and construction for an hospital and several health centres.

- Supervised technical work, team management and progress follow-up.
- Ensured logistical aspects: budgeting, subcontracting, supply chain, purchase and storage process.
- Vaccination Logistic Manager: Kabalo, Democratic Republic of Congo (3 months)

Managed and planned logistic activities for a measles epidemic emergency vaccination campaign.

- Supervised logistic team to ensure transportation of medical teams, materials and vaccines.
- Scheduled 50 000 vaccinations with 160 team members within 4 weeks in over 50 villages.
- Hospital Logistic Manager : Leogane, Haiti (6 months)

Supervised logistics team & technical activities: transport, maintenance, team facilities, water, energy.

- In charge of the storage process and streamlining of materials excess with donations before closure.
- Developed and implemented a rehabilitation project for a partner hospital near the 2010
- earthquake epicentre: masonry, water supply modernisation, refurbishment and electricity.

#### Construction Supervisor

SEPTEMBER 2004 - APRIL 2013

BATICENTRE SARL - Cebazat, France

In charge of building site management for masonry, reinforced concrete and excavation operations.

- Supervised Team Leader of different building sites: management of 25 to 40 employees.
- Followed onsite activities to ensure smooth and efficient progress of projects.
- Ensured public relations in meetings to coordinate the diverse step of the constructions.
- Scheduled technical equipment requirements and planed equipment maintenance.
- Provided an efficient supply chain for materials and managed storage processes.
- Assessed work quality to ensure the respect of specifications and safety requirements.
- Evaluated proposals, achieved estimates and quantified needs for new projects and public tenders.
- Established work plans to report technical aspects of the building sites.

# VOLUNTEERING

#### 

OCTOBER 2013 - JUNE 2014

ARIMC Association - Lyon, France

Project with a participatory approach helping an association supporting people with disabilities.

- Design, implementation and activities management of a shared garden for people with disabilities.
- Creation and manufacturing of gardening tables adapted to people in wheelchairs.
- Established work plans and reported building instructions to extend this project for a retirement home.

# KEY ACHIEVEMENTS & SOFT SKILLS

**TEAM WORKS** 

PROGRAMMING

**ADAPTABILITY** 

MULTI TASKING

PROBLEM SOLVING

TEAM LEADING

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

CAPACITY TO LEARN

WORK UNDER PRESSURE

# PERSONAL INTERESTS

CODING

FAMILY

PARAGLIDING

**TECHNOLOGIES** 

PHOTOGRAPHY

SKI TOURING

INTERNET

TRAVEL

SCUBA DIVING

## RFFFRFFS

#### Alex SHAW

Tea Cup Cottage

Executive Director

alex@tea-cupcottage.com

+61 409 896 311

#### Rebecca ANDERSON

Doctors Without Borders
Project Medical Referent
randelallana@gmail.com
+41 766 077 523

**Linked** in /romain-gioux

GitHub /nordend4000